Pablo Clark

pablo.clark.com.mx

Barcelona, Spain +34 655 167 941 pabloclarkd@gmail.com Data analyst with seven years of experience with websites and research. I am an analytical thinker with knowledge of quantitative and qualitative methods, an effective communicator with an eye for detail, and an organized project manager.

Work experience

December 2022 – present (Barcelona, Spain)

Customer Service Representative – The 7th Circle

Communicate with customers over the phone to register them, sell services, process payments and manage appointments

Update database records of customers interactions, transactions and complaints

May 2022 – November 2022 (Mexico, remote)
Online Data Analyst – Telus International

Analyzed and provided feedback on text, web pages and images for leading search engines

July 2018 – May 2022 (Mexico City, Mexico)

Researcher – Mexican Institute for Competitiveness

Managed websites that use data to help users make informed decisions about their education, coordinating the work of the developer, analyst and communications teams, and providing support to our site's users.

Led research and consultancy projects in topics such as higher education economic returns, learning evaluations, school choice, and women in STEM

Used R to analyze data and create visualizations that turned insights into stories that communicated findings in reports, presentations and social media materials

January 2015 – July 2018 Analyst – *Mexican Institute for Competitiveness*

Provided support to website users

Assisted with research activities and drafted social media
materials

Education

2010 - 2015

Bachelor's degree in Sociology with honors from Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México.

Key skills

Data analysis and visualization
R
Customer support
Writing research reports, opinion

articles, and social media materials
Microsoft Office (Word, Powerpoint,
Excel) & Google Workspace

Public speaking
Project management
Google Analytics
Native Spanish speaker
Fluent in English (TOELF iBT 112)

Other experience

January 2020 – August 2020 Teacher assistant - *Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México*

Assisted teaching duties and taught students to use R in the 'Applied statistics in the social sciences II" course.